Guide to the Sarah Lane Literary Society records, 1947-2000s UA 287
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Sarah Lane Literary Society records
1947-2000s
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Sarah Lane Literary Society
UA 287
11 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
The Sarah Lane Literary Society (SLLS), founded in 1947, was named after Sarah Lane, a 1919 graduate who served as the dean of women, 1931-1950. It disbanded in 1965, but its alumnae stayed active through the 2000s. This record contains correspondence, ledgers, information about events, alumnae directories, alumnae newsletters, and scrapbooks.
Historical Note
The Sarah Lane Literary Society (SLLS), founded in 1947, was named after Sarah Lane, a 1919 graduate who served as the dean of women, 1931-1950. It disbanded in 1965, but its alumnae stayed active through the 2000s.
Scope and Contents
The records contain correspondence, ledgers, information about events, alumnae directories, alumnae newsletters, and scrapbooks.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Acquisition Information
Carolyn Dortch, and in 2019, Pamela Wright.
Index Terms
Subjects
Women; Rice University -- History; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Universities and colleges; Social life and customs
Document Types
directories; scrapbooks; corrrespondence
- Series I: Administrative, 146799
  - Ledger, 1957-1965; 146800 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - President's Book, 1961-1964; 146801 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Events, undated; 146802 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Constitution, undated; 146803 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - University-wide, undated; 146804 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series II: Alumnae, 146805
  - Gavel, 146806 (Box 2, Item 1)
  - Metal box contianing SLLS Alums directory cards, 146808 (Box 2, Item 2)
  - Vice President's Papers, 1963-1971; 146810 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - President's Notebook, 1965-1971, 146811 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Constitution of SLLS Alumnae Chapter, 146812 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Directory Books, 1952-1958; 146814 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Membership Directories, 1969-1970; 146813 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newsletters, 1963-1971; 146815 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newsclippings, 1957-1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alumni group minutes, 1954-1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Alumni group constitution, correspondence, and directory, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Series III: Scrapbooks, 146816
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1953; 146817 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1951-1952; 146818 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1956-1957; 146819 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1963; 146820 (Box 4)